Register of the Leon Gouré papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Leon Gouré papers
1919-2007
2008C93
Hoover Institution Archives
59 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (26.0 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, reports, studies, conference materials, printed matter, and slides, relating to Soviet defenses and military policy, especially civil defense measures, and to nuclear warfare strategy.
Gouré, Leon
Access
Collection is open for research. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
The papers were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives from Daniel Gouré in 2008.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1922, November 1 Born, Moscow, Russia
1923 Emigrated with family from Russia to Germany
1933 Emigrated from Germany to France
1940 Emigrated from France to the United States
1943-1946 United States Army Counterintelligence Corps
1947 B.A., New York University
1949 M.I.A., Columbia University
1951-1969 Staff member, Rand Corporation
1961 Ph.D., Georgetown University
1969-1978 Director of Soviet studies, Center for Advanced International Studies, University of Miami
1978-1980 Associate director, Advanced International Studies Institute, Washington, D.C.
1980-2004 Director, Center for Soviet Studies, Science Applications International Corporation
2007, March 16 Died, Arlington, Virginia
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers of Leon Gouré, American Sovietologist, defense expert, and longtime staff member of, first, the Rand Corporation, and, subsequently, the Science Applications International Corporation, concern Soviet defense policy. Gouré's initial area of expertise was Soviet civil defense. While maintaining this interest throughout a long career, he broadened his research to cover Soviet military policy and strategic thinking in general. A persistent theme was Soviet perception of American and NATO defense policy.
The heart of the collection is the SPEECHES AND WRITINGS series, including lectures, briefing presentations, conference papers, Congressional testimony, technical reports, journal articles and longer writings by Gouré, alone or in collaboration with colleagues. Many of the writings, all unclassified, are reports commissioned by United States government agencies, including defense, arms control, nuclear energy, emergency management and other agencies. In addition to civil defense, specific topics include nuclear war strategy, deterrence, nuclear proliferation, arms reduction negotiations, emergency planning, ballistic missile defense, and the Chernobyl nuclear accident. Some writings are concerned with placing military and strategic issues within a broader ideological and geopolitical context, with analysis of the nature of Soviet society and its decision-making process. Gouré's academic lectures on Soviet society and foreign policy as a professor at the University of Miami are included. While directly addressing Soviet perceptions of American policy, the writings also serve to document American perceptions of Soviet policy during the Cold War. A feature of particular interest is that they extend through the decade of the 1990s, thus dealing not only with the Cold War period at its peak, but also with the transition from Soviet Union to post-Soviet Russia. They document the perception of the disintegration of the Soviet Union and of the new Russian political entity within American strategic circles.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in seven series: Biographical File, 1973-2007; Speeches and Writings, 1954-2004; Writings By Others, 1950-1998; Subject File, 1942-2005; Printed Monographs, 1919-1968; Audiovisual Material, undated; and Oversize file, 1958.
Arms control.; Civil defense--Soviet Union.; Nuclear weapons.; Russia (Federation)--Defenses.; Russia (Federation)--Military policy.; Slides (Photography).; Soviet Union--Defenses.; Soviet Union--Military policy.
- Biographical File, 1973-2007 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Résumés, clippings, certificate, and obituary
  - Biographical File, 1973-2007 (Folder 1: 1)
- Speeches and Writings, 1954-2004 (Box 1-32)
  Lectures, briefing presentations and conference papers by Gouré; writings of which he was author or co-author; unsigned reports for which he shared responsibility; products of conferences in which he was a participant; and supporting documentation for all of the above
  - "From Munich to February 1, 1939," draft chapter for Rand Corporation study of Soviet foreign policy, circa 1954 (Folder 1: 2)
  - "The Eighteenth Congress of the Communist Party (March 1939) and the Fall of Prague," draft chapter for Rand Corporation study of Soviet foreign policy, 1954 April 19 (Folder 1: 3)
  - "The Start of the Negotiation, March 15 to May 3, 1939," draft chapter for Rand Corporation study of Soviet foreign policy, 1955 July 28 (Folder 1: 4-5)
  - "Report of a Study of Non-Military Defense,", 1958 June 25 (Folder 1: 6)
  - "Soviet Civil Defense,", 1960 March 14 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Rand Corporation Air Force Advisory Group meeting, 1961 January 4-6 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Testimony on Soviet civil defense, United States Congress House Committee on Government Operations Subcommittee on Military Operations, 1961 August 9 (Folder 1: 9)
  - "Civil Defense Training in Russia," Journal of the American Society of Training Directors, 1961 (Folder 1: 10)
  - Civil Defense in the Soviet Union, 1962 (Folder 2: 1)
  - "The Resolution of the Soviet Controversy over Civil Defense,", 1962 June (Folder 2: 2)
  - "Some Recent Soviet Materials on Civil Defense,", 1963 April 9 (Folder 2: 3)
  - "Soviet Limited War Doctrine,", 1963 May (Folder 2: 4)
  - "Recent Developments in the Soviet Civil Defense Program,", 1963 June (Folder 2: 5)
  - "The Role of Civil Defense in Soviet Strategy,", 1963 June (Folder 2: 6)
  - Testimony on Soviet civil defense, United States Congress House Committee on Armed Services, 1963 June 17 (Folder 2: 7)
  - "Notes on the Second Edition of Marshal V. D. Sokolovskii's Military Strategy,", 1964 February (Folder 2: 8)
  - Presentation at Advanced Research Projects Agency Defense Science Seminar, University of California, Los Angeles, 1966 August 19 (Folder 2: 9)
  - "Soviet Emergency Planning,", 1969 February (Folder 2: 10)
  - "Recent Soviet Comments on Civil Defense and Evacuation,", 1969 November 20 (Folder 2: 11)
  - Lectures on Soviet foreign and military policy and the dynamics and future of Soviet society, Center for Advanced International Studies, University of Miami, 1969-1978 (Folder 2: 12-14)
  - Lectures on Soviet foreign and military policy and the dynamics and future of Soviet society, Center for Advanced International Studies, University of Miami, 1969-1978 (Folder 3-5)
  - "Soviet Views on Coexistence and Defense,", circa 1970 (Folder 6: 1)
  - "Aspects of the Future Low Level Insurgency Environment: The Nature of the Threat and Its Implications for the U.S. and U.S. Air Capability for COIN,", 1970 February 5 (Folder 6: 2)
  - "Cuba and Security Implications for the United States,", 1971 March 31 (Folder 6: 3)
  - "Soviet Global Policy and Naval Power,", circa 1972 (Folder 6: 4)
  - "Soviet Civil Defense: Urban Evacuation and Dispersal,", 1972 May (Folder 6: 5)
  - "Soviet Policy and Peaceful Coexistence,", 1972 May 3 (Folder 6: 6)
  - "The Militarization of Soviet Youth: The Military-Patriotic Education Campaign,", 1972 October 30 (Folder 6: 7)
  - "Soviet Studies of Cuba," Problems of Communism, 1972 November-December (Folder 6: 8)
  - The Military Indoctrination of Soviet Youth, 1973 (Folder 6: 9)
  - "Soviet Civil Defense: Post-Strike Repair and Restoration,", 1973 June (Folder 6: 10)
  - "Countermeasures in Fleet Defense,", 1973 July 25 (Folder 6: 11)
  - "A Preliminary Unsolicited Proposal for a Study to Assess Soviet Naval Personnel/Manpower Problems and Vulnerabilities,", circa 1974 (Folder 7: 1)
  - The Role of Nuclear Forces in Current Soviet Strategy (Folder 7: 2)
  - The Soviet Union and the October 1973 Middle East War: The Implications for Detente Draft chapters 5 and 6, 1974 (Folder 7: 3)
  - "The Future: What Does It Hold? The Soviet Union, Detente and US Security,", 1974 April 18 (Folder 7: 4)
  - "Soviet Penetration in Latin America,", 1974 August 22 (Folder 7: 5)
  - Air Force Association Symposium on New Dimensions in Strategic Deterrence, Shreveport, Louisiana, and Barksdale Air Force Base, 1974 November 13-14 (Folder 7: 6)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of the United States' Global Position,", 1975 June (Folder 7: 7)
  - "Soviet Civil Defense in the Seventies,", 1975 September (Folder 7: 8)
  - "Strategic Balance in the Southern Hemisphere: The Soviet Threat,", 1975 September 27 (Folder 7: 9)
  - "The Soviet Navy in War and Peace,", 1975 October (Folder 7: 10)
  - "Forecasting Future Needs for the Soviet Military,", 1975 November (Folder 7: 11)
  - "Moscow's Language Lessons for Americans: The Meaning and Intent of Detente,", 1975 December 17 (Folder 7: 12)
  - "The Soviet Meaning of 'Correlation of Forces,'", circa 1976 (Folder 7: 13)
  - War Survival in Soviet Strategy: USSR Civil Defense, 1976 (Folder 7: 14)
  - "The Soviet Autarky and War-Survival Doctrines,", 1976 February 23 (Folder 7: 15)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of the Strategic Balance within the Concept of the Correlation of World Forces,", 1976 April 21 (Folder 7: 16)
  - "Science and Technology as a Decisive Factor for Soviet Power and in Moscow's Competition with the West,", 1976 August 11 (Folder 7: 17)
  - "Soviet Objectives and the Role of Military Power,", 1976 October 28 (Folder 7: 18)
  - "Soviet Views on and Response to the U.S. Flexible Option Strategy,", 1976 November 10 (Folder 7: 19)
  - "Shelters in the Soviet Civil Defense Program,", 1977 February (Folder 8: 1)
  - "Soviet Military Doctrine," Air Force Magazine, 1977 March (Folder 8: 2)
  - "The Soviet Civil Defense Shelter Program,", 1977 May (Folder 8: 3)
  - "Soviet Constraints and Vulnerabilities: Opportunities and Prospects for U.S. Leverage,", 1977 May 3 (Folder 8: 4)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of the Nature and Importance of the 'Correlation of World Forces' in the Struggle between the Systems,", 1977 August (Folder 8: 5)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of the Role and Utility of Civil Defense in the US-USSR Military Equation,", 1977 August (Folder 8: 6)
  - "Soviet Foreign Policy Objectives: Detente and the Role of Force,", 1977 August 8 (Folder 8: 7)
  - "U.S.-Soviet Competition in the Third World and Its Implications,", 1977 August 10 (Folder 8: 8)
  - "Summary Notes on Likely Soviet Responses to Some U.S. Options to Deter a Soviet Attack in Europe,", 1977 September 1 (Folder 8: 9)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of the Role of Military Power in the Struggle between Systems,", 1977 October (Folder 8: 10)
  - "Soviet Views of the Role and Utility of Military Power in War and Peace,", 1977 November (Folder 8: 11)
  - "Notes on Meeting with Jim Wade concerning CTB,", 1977 November 10 (Folder 8: 12)
  - "Some Comments on Mr. F. Kaplan's Article 'Soviet Civil Defense,'", 1977 December (Folder 8: 13)
  - Shelters in Soviet War Survival Strategy, 1978 (Folder 8: 14)
  - Untitled study of Soviet views on military policy, circa 1978 (Folder 8: 15-16)
  - "NATO and Warsaw Pact: A Historic Background,", 1978 January 10 (Folder 9: 1)
  - "A Comparative Analysis of U.S./USSR Theories of Civil Emergency Preparedness,", 1978 January 18 (Folder 9: 2)
  - "Patterns of Decision-Making in Soviet Crisis Management,", 1978 February (Folder 9: 3)
  - Institute for Foreign Policy Analysis Conference on the Emerging Strategic Environment: Implications for Ballistic Missile Defense, Washington, D.C., 1978 March 8-9 (Folder 9: 4)
  - "Proposal for Extension of Study of Shelters in Soviet Cities…", 1978 April 6 (Folder 9: 5)
  - Air Force conference on science and technology, 1978 May (Folder 9: 6)
  - Institute for Foreign Policy Analysis Conference on the Soviet Union and Ballistic Missile Defense, Washington, D.C., 1978 May 10-11 (Folder 9: 7)
  - Institute for Foreign Policy Analysis Conference on U.S. Strategic-Nuclear Policy and Ballistic Missile Defense: The 1980s and Beyond, Washington, D.C., 1978 July 26-27 (Folder 9: 8)
  - "Civil Defense and the Strategic Equation,", 1978 November 29 (Folder 9: 9)
  - The Emerging Strategic Environment: Implications for Ballistic Missile Defense, 1979 (Folder 9: 10)
  - "The Role and Mission of Soviet Civil Defense,", circa 1979 (Folder 9: 11)
  - Proposals for studies of Soviet civil defense, 1979 April (Folder 9: 12)
  - "The Soviet Strategic View," Strategic Review, 1979 Fall (Folder 9: 13)
  - "The Civil Defense Factor in the Strategic Balance," National Defense, 1979 September-October (Folder 9: 14)
  - "New Data on Soviet War Survival Capabilities,", 1979 December (Folder 9: 15)
  - "The Role and Capabilities of Rural Areas in Soviet Civil Defense,", circa 1980 (Folder 10: 1-2)
  - "Civil Defense in Soviet Strategic Perceptions,", 1980 January 1 (Folder 10: 3)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of U.S. Vulnerabilities to Strategic Attack and Implications for Soviet Views on Deterrence, Warfighting and War Outcome,", 1980 August (Folder 10: 4)
  - "The Soviet Strategic View," Strategic Review, 1981 Winter (Folder 10: 5)
  - "Soviet Nuclear Strategic Policy,", 1981 April 7 (Folder 10: 6)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of Fire and the Fire/Blast Wave Interaction in Zones of Nuclear Destruction: A Preliminary Assessment Approach,", 1981 July (Folder 10: 7)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of the Present State and Trends in U.S. Nuclear Doctrine and Weapon Systems,", 1981 July (Folder 10: 8)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of the Quality and Shortcomings of the Soviet Officer Corps: Professionalism, Training, Performance, Attitudes and Morale,", 1981 July (Folder 10: 9)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of the U.S./NATO Threat: Soviet Assessment of U.S./NATO Strategic and Associated Weapon System Characteristics and Employment Concepts,", 1981 July (Folder 10: 10)
  - "An Analysis of Soviet Perceptions of the Lessons Learned from Experiences with 'National Liberation' Movements and Wars in the Third World and their Implication for Future Soviet Policies and Strategies and U.S. Security Interests,", 1981 August (Folder 10: 11)
  - "The U.S. 'Countervailing Strategy' in Soviet Perception," Strategic Review, 1981 Fall (Folder 10: 12)
  - "The Significance of Soviet 'Urban-Type Settlements' for Assessments of Soviet Economic Targets and 'Essential Workers,'", 1981 September (Folder 10: 13)
  - "U.S. and Soviet Doctrines in the 1980s: Implications for Strategic Defense,", 1981 September 21 (Folder 10: 14)
  - "Soviet Perceptions and Assessments of the Implications for Soviet Security Interests of the Current U.S. Military Doctrine and Defense Programs and their Likely Further Evolution,", 1981 October (Folder 10: 15)
  - "Soviet Assessments of the U.S./NATO Threat and Its Implications for Soviet Arms Reduction Negotiations,", 1981 December 4 (Folder 10: 16)
  - "Strategic Defense and Soviet Military Doctrine,", 1982 February 9 (Folder 11: 1)
  - "The Soviet Strategic View," Strategic Review, 1982 Spring (Folder 11: 2)
  - "An Analysis of the Soviet Propaganda Campaign against TNF Modernization,", 1982 August (Folder 11: 3)
  - "Soviet Post-Strike Civil Defense Rescue, Damage-Limiting, Repair and Restoration Operations,", 1982 August (Folder 11: 4-5)
  - "Some Remarks on the Future of Strategic Offense and Defense,", 1982 October 14 (Folder 11: 6)
  - "Present and Future Soviet Anti-Ballistic Missile Defense Technologies and their Implications for Arms Control,", ca. 1983 (Folder 11: 7)
  - "Possible Directions of Soviet Weapons Development in Response to Soviet Assessment of New and Planned U.S./NATO Weapon Systems: Implications for Soviet Defense Industry Capabilities,", 1983 March (Folder 11: 8)
  - "Soviet Geographic Siting of Heavy Industry,", 1983 March (Folder 11: 9)
  - "The Soviet Crisis Relocation Program,", 1983 May (Folder 11: 10)
  - "A Comparison of Soviet and U.S. Civil Defense Programs,", 1983 June (Folder 11: 11)
  - "Savant Sagan's Specious Scenario," Washington Times, 1983 December 1 (Folder 11: 12)
  - "Soviet Scientists as Shills for a Freeze," Washington Times, 1983 December 19 (Folder 11: 13)
  - "A Preliminary Examination of Soviet Assessments of Fires and their Secondary Climatic and Other Effects in a Nuclear War: IR and D Proposal,", 1983 December 21 (Folder 11: 14)
  - "Problems of Succession in Cuba: The Soviet Factor,", circa 1984 (Folder 11: 15)
  - "The Soviet Civil Defense Medical Preparedness Program,", 1984 March (Folder 11: 16)
  - "Soviet Views on the British, French and Chinese Strategic Nuclear Threat to the Soviet Union,", 1984 March (Folder 12: 1)
  - "Soviet Views on the Strategic Nuclear Threat from the Mediterranean and Indian Ocean,", 1984 March (Folder 12: 2)
  - "Geostrategic Asymmetries between the Superpowers and the Role of Technology,", 1984 April 25-27 (Folder 12: 3)
  - "Soviet Non-Slavic Nationalities and the Military: Problems and Options,", 1984 July (Folder 12: 4)
  - "Soviet Civil Defense Public Instuction and Training Programs,", 1984 August (Folder 12: 5)
  - "Soviet Strategy for General Nuclear War,", 1984 October (Folder 12: 6)
  - "Warsaw Pact Tactical Missile Threat Characteristics and Analysis,", 1984 October (Folder 12: 7)
  - "Potential Implications of ROA: Some Possible Soviet Non-Military Costs,", 1984 December 31 (Folder 12: 8)
  - "Soviet Views on the Character and Consequences of the Post-Attack Nuclear Environment,", circa 1985 (Folder 12: 9)
  - "The Soviet Strategic View," Strategic Review, 1985 Winter (Folder 12: 10)
  - "Elements of U.S. and Soviet Views on Deterrence" and "Soviet Views on Military Deterrence,", 1985 January 21 (Folder 12: 11)
  - "The Soviet Philosophy of ASAT,", 1985 March 11 (Folder 12: 12)
  - "'Nuclear Winter' in Soviet Mirrors," Strategic Review (Folder 12: 13)
  - "Soviet Civil Defense Agricultural Preparedness,", 1985 June (Folder 12: 14-15)
  - "Soviet Exploitation of the 'Nuclear Winter' Hypothesis,", 1985 June 5 (Folder 13: 1-2)
  - "Soviet-Cuban Military Relations,", 1985 August (Folder 13: 3)
  - "Soviet Views on the Long-Term Environmental Consequences of a Nuclear War: Implications for Soviet Warfighting and U.S. Deterrence,", 1985 August (Folder 13: 4)
  - "Possible Candidate Alternate Theater War Scenarios and Implications for Measures of Effectiveness,", 1985 August 22 (Folder 13: 5)
  - "The RAND Corporation POW and Defector Debriefing Program,", 1985 September 24 (Folder 13: 6)
  - "Soviet 'Nuclear Winter' Research and Its Implications," testimony, United States Senate Armed Services Committee, 1985 October 2 (Folder 13: 7)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of the SLBM Threat and Counters to It,", 1985 October 8 (Folder 13: 8)
  - "Some Possible Costs of Soviet Defense against a U.S. Advanced Technology Bomber,", 1985 October 9 (Folder 13: 9)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of Opportunities for Gain and Potential Crisis Areas in the Third World,", 1985 October 22 (Folder 13: 10)
  - "Suggested Research Topics on Soviet Perspectives of and Responses to SDI,", 1985 December 3 (Folder 13: 11)
  - German-American Roundtable, Bonn, West Germany, 1985 December 4-6 (Folder 13: 12)
  - "Questions and Responses to Questionnaire #2 in Support of Concept Definition Task CD-10,", 1985 December 19 (Folder 13: 13)
  - "Laws of Nature vs. SDI,", circa 1986 (Folder 13: 14)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of the SLBM Threat,", 1986 March 10 (Folder 13: 15)
  - "An Addendum to 'USSR Criteria for Small Wars,'", 1986 April 8 (Folder 13: 16)
  - "Soviet Damage-Control Management of an Unanticipated Incident: The Case of the Downing of Korean Airlines Flight 007,", 1986 April 18 (Folder 13: 17)
  - "Possible Soviet Targeting Priorities in NATO's Northern Flank,", 1986 May 29 (Folder 14: 1)
  - "Dealing with the Aftermath of a Large Nuclear Reactor Accident: Some Apparent Lessons from the Chernobyl Disaster,", 1986 August 17-22 (Folder 14: 2)
  - "Cuban Military Doctrine and Organization,", 1986 November 14 (Folder 14: 3)
  - "Not Nuclear Test Bans but More Testing," Global Affairs, circa 1987 (Folder 14: 4)
  - "An Overlooked U.S./Soviet Strategic Asymmetry: A Comparison of U.S./Soviet Civil Defense Programs,", circa 1987 (Folder 14: 5)
  - "Soviet Views on the Consequences of Targeting Nuclear Power Plants and Other Nuclear Installations,", 1987 July (Folder 14: 6)
  - High Frontier briefing, 1987 August 18 (Folder 14: 7)
  - "Some Findings of the Chernobyl Trial,", 1987 September (Folder 14: 8)
  - "The Chernobyl Accident Data Base: Section V: Radiation Situation at the AES and in the Danger Zone,", 1987 October (Folder 14: 9)
  - "The Chernobyl Accident Data Base: Section VIII: Medical,", 1987 October (Folder 15: 1-2)
  - "The Chernobyl Accident Data Base: Section IX: Operations and Protection of the Work Force in the Danger Zone,", 1987 October (Folder 15: 3)
  - "An Update of Soviet Research on and Exploitation of 'Nuclear Winter,' 1984-1986,", 1987 October 10 (Folder 15: 4-5)
  - German-American Roundtable, Washington, D.C., 1987 October 28-30 (Folder 15: 6)
  - "The Medical Aspects of the Chernobyl Nuclear Reactor Accident,", 1987 November (Folder 15: 7)
  - "On the Implications of Precision-Guided Weapons,", circa 1988 (Folder 16: 1)
  - "Some Soviet Views on 'Perestroyka,'", circa 1988 (Folder 16: 2)
  - "Soviet Perceptions of the SLBM Threat in 1987,", 1988 February 15 (Folder 16: 3-4)
  - "Some Long-Term Consequences of the Chernobyl Reactor Accident for Habitation, Agriculture and Water Supply,", 1988 March (Folder 16: 5)
  - "Notes on Soviet Views on Nuclear Winter and the Implications of Chernobyl,", 1988 April 8 (Folder 16: 6)
  - "Some Long-Term Consequences of the Chernobyl Nuclear Reactor Accident,", 1988 April 12 (Folder 16: 7)
  - "Soviet Assessment of the Offensive Space Weapons Threat to Atmospheric and Surface Targets,", 1988 May (Folder 16: 8-9)
  - "The Chernobyl Accident Data Base: Section IV: Initial Management of the Accident: Organization and Personnel Response,", 1988 June (Folder 17: 1-2)
  - "The Chernobyl Accident Data Base: Section VIII: Medical: Update,", 1988 June (Folder 17: 3)
  - "Present and Future Soviet Anti-Ballistic Missile Defense Technologies and their Implications for Arms Control,", 1988 June 6 (Folder 17: 4)
  - "Civil Emergency Planning,", 1988 July 26 (Folder 17: 5)
  - "The Chernobyl Accident Data Base: Section XII: The Role of the Military,", 1988 August (Folder 17: 6-7)
  - "Soviet Political-Military Objectives in Southeast Asia and the Pacific,", 1988 September (Folder 17: 8)
  - "Evaluation of the Impact of Non-Nuclear U.S. Attacks on Soviet Space Launch Facilities,", 1988 October (Folder 17: 9)
  - "A Preliminary Assessment of Soviet Views on Long-Term Effects of a Nuclear War,", 1988 October (Folder 18: 1-2)
  - "Kremlin Shake-up: Gorbachev's Coup?" Global Alert, 1988 October 25 (Folder 18: 3)
  - "Cuba as an Instrument of Soviet International Policy,", 1988 November 25 (Folder 18: 4)
  - "Authoritarianism and Democratization in the Soviet Union,", 1989 (Folder 18: 5)
  - "U.S.-Soviet Relations: 'Perestroika' and the Bush Administration," American Review, 1989 (Folder 18: 6)